I got a good one for you guys today the
tonal home gym is this the Rolls-Royce
of Smart Home Gyms takes up minimal
space it has built-in coaching and it
has resistance built into it as well
I've been lucky enough to get my hands
on one of these bad boys so today I'm
going to break down my experience for
y'all what's up everybody it's Jake and
for today's review I had to switch up
locations a little bit on you guys don't
worry I'm still going to tell you
everything you need to know about the
tonal from the price and the features as
well as the pros and cons and of course
who should or maybe should not buy one
of these but before I get started with
all of that I have to let you know we've
reviewed a lot of smart gems on
barbin.com and if you want to browse our
best list just go and search barbend
best smart gyms and you can find out for
yourself which ones that we like the
best
foreign
well for starters it takes up minimal
space as you see right here but it's
also an Adaptive piece of equipment so
once you complete a strength assessment
you're never going to have to worry
about figuring out how much weight to
lift on your own tonal is going to
provide a suggested weight for every
single workout that you do and that's
going to increase over time as you
progress in your strength it is an extra
fee but once you add on the accessories
package it's going to include their own
version of a barbell some smart handles
a rope attachment a yoga mat a foam
roller and a weight bench for you to
work out with and a set of 17 sensors
right here is going to read your form
and provide suggested feedback wherever
it's necessary so if you're doing an
exercise the wrong way it's going to pop
up right here on the screen and tell you
exactly what you need to do to correct
that
[Music]
foreign
okay so with all those great things
about tonal being said there's still a
few issues you might run into and let's
go ahead and get the elephant in the
room out of the way it's expensive
especially once you factor in the
necessary attachments shipping and
installation and everyone's favorite
thing to pay taxes you're going to be
spending over four thousand dollars on
this piece of equipment since tonal has
to be mounted onto your wall it can be a
little bit tricky to find a sweet spot
for it to go so be sure to find those
exact stud space things before you
commit to a location in your home so
it's required for your studs to be
either 16 or 24 inches apart and tonal
cannot be mounted in the cinder block
which is why we're not in the garage
today there is a different feel all
around especially when it comes to the
barbell doing a bench press it's a
little bit wobbly and it's due to the
cables it's something you can power
through but it definitely feels a little
funky in the beginning and the max
weight resistance is 200 pounds now that
might be plenty of weight for the
recreational lifter but if you're a
power lifter you know it's probably not
enough weight for you and you're
probably going to be better off with a
good old-fashioned barbell and some
weight plates that can handle the amount
of weight that you're able to lift
[Music]
well Wu-Tang said it best cash rules
everything around me so let's talk about
some money now unlike some other smart
gym companies tonal does not offer more
than one package so the actual tonal
itself is about 3 500 bucks the
necessary attachments are around 500
shipping and installation is going to
cost you about 300 and on top of that
you have to pay about 50 bucks a month
for monthly membership fee now those
monthly payments for your membership
those are going to kick in as soon as
you get your tonal set up with a 12
month minimum plan now good news is if
you are on a tight budget you can at
least split your payment up into
interest-free payments of over 24 36 or
48 months but I'll dig into more of that
in just a second all right now let's
compare the price of tonal to a gym
membership as well as some personal
training classes so the average gym
membership in the United States is right
around 50 bucks a month and then around
40 or so for personal training classes
so let's say you saw a personal trainer
twice a week that's going to be about
250 bucks on top of your gym membership
so in total you'll be spending around 3
600 a year just on those two things now
let's say you want a personal trainer to
come to your home well that's going to
be more expensive let's say it's about
60 bucks per visit then when it's all
said and done you'll be spending around
five grand just on your gym membership
and those at home visits from a personal
trainer all right now say you want to
finance your purchase through a firm
you'll have three different options to
choose from either the 24 36 or 48 month
options so let's start with that 48
month plan you'll be making monthly
payments of around 140 dollars that's
going to equal to right around Seventeen
hundred dollars a year that 36 month
option well that's going to be around
170 bucks a month or right around 2
Grand a year and that 24 month payment
plan that's going to be around 230
dollars a month or right around twenty
seven hundred dollars a year so in the
long run you'll actually be saving a
little bit of money when tonal and
you'll still get the benefit of having
personal training without actually
having to leave the comfort of your home
all right now in terms of your
subscription there's really not much to
it honestly as I said you got to pay
right around 50 bucks a month and that's
just to gain access to the available
classes that are loaded onto tonal
[Music]
all right so let's go ahead and talk
about the accessories now you know once
again this is not included with your
original purchase of the tonal it's
going to be an additional 500 or so on
top of that now this is going to include
their version of a barbell a pair of
smart handles a rope attachment yoga mat
a foam roller and a weight bench for you
to use now really cool thing here is
that the smart handles as well as this
clamp can attach to your barbell and
your rope attachment they use smart
technology now all right what does that
mean exactly well essentially what this
does is it turns on and off the digital
weight with just that click of a button
it almost acts as a spotter so once
you're ready to lift you're in a
position you just click that button the
weight's going to kick in and you're
ready to go now let's say you're
struggling or you just want to turn the
weight off off simply just press that
button so that's really how it does in
fact act like a spotter this smart
technology is also going to track your
reps for any exercise that you're doing
and that's going to add on to your
overall leaderboard score that I'm going
to talk about in just a minute now as
far as the foam roller the yoga mat and
the weight bench scope they're pretty
basic so it'd be nice if these were
separate you know you could purchase
them separately and also gotta say I
would like to see an adjustable weight
bench instead of a normal flat bench
it's going to take up more space
probably in your home but there's so
many benefits in my opinion with an
adjustable bench and I personally would
love to see that here
foreign
[Music]
space that you need for your tonal once
again tonal mounts directly to your wall
and it's required for your stud spacings
to be either 16 or 24 inches apart
anything bigger or smaller than that
it's just simply not going to work the
actual footprint of tonal though is
obviously pretty small and that's a
really nice thing about it it's just
over four feet tall just under two feet
wide and it only sticks out about five
inches or so from your actual wall now
really the only thing you got to worry
about is just making sure your ceilings
are tall enough for those times where
the cable arms are at their highest
point so I'd recommend having around
seven square feet of space or so just so
you can work out properly with tonal
and you need to make sure you have your
tonal placed in the most ideal spot in
your home because if you ever need to
move it for whatever reason you're gonna
have to have somebody from tonal come
out and do that for you all right now
you also have the option of purchasing a
storage shelf and that way you can hang
your barbell your rope attachment and
your smart handles from Individual hooks
while your yoga mat and your foam roller
can sit on top of the Shelf now as far
as your weight bench goes tonal does not
have any sort of solution for it to
store so you'll probably want to get a
little creative and find somewhere for
it to be tucked out of sight this is an
extra 250 bucks though since you're
already spending over four thousand
dollars I'd suggest coming up with a
cheaper alternative just to store all of
your accessories
foreign
classes that tonal provides there's over
a thousand of them right here at your
fingertips ready to go at a moment's
notice but you can also create your own
custom programs whether that be a full
body workout or you create your own
split for a full week There's an option
for basically everybody since their
strength training classes dance cardio
classes and even family classes for you
to choose from now every single one of
these classes are led by an instructor
and they consist of a warm-up as well as
a cool down now I'm not gonna lie to you
these workouts are pretty legit and they
had me feeling pretty tired by the time
I was done with them and I know it
sounds a little bit weird that the
weight is all done electromagnetically
but I promise you you're gonna get a
good work at it you can join an
on-demand class at any time of the day
you can join a live class with the rest
of the tonal Community you can do
virtual workouts with your friends or
you can do a partner workout with one of
your buddies so a partner workout is
going to require for your friend to be
signed into their tonal account and as
soon as you guys select what workouts
you want to do tonal is going to ask
who's going first and then after that
the weight is going to be automatically
adjusted between each person's set that
way it's going to accommodate for both
of you now while you're working out you
can track stats such as your heart rate
total volume lifted as well as your
range of motion while you're lifting
that way you always know where you need
to improve
[Music]
another really cool thing about tonal is
the companion app so this is where each
and every single one of your workouts
are tracked and you're able to see your
results in real time with the progress
tracker tunnel is also going to take
your original strength assessment score
that you have it's going to set a
benchmark for your fitness journey and
the app is also going to show your
growing strength broken down my body
region and muscle group and that's also
going to be updated in real time these
post-workout Recaps are going to include
your time under tension total weight
lifted and the amount of moves that
you've completed you'll also see your
personal records unlock achievement
Badges and even track your place in the
monthly leaderboard
foreign
does not offer a leaderboard for each
individual class you complete it does
however offer a leaderboard over a
30-day span so your rank on that
leaderboard is going to be directly
impacted by your dedication to working
out from how many classes you've
completed as well as your total amount
of time that you spent working out this
is a great system for anybody who loves
a little bit of taste of competition and
it also is going to provide you with the
overarching look at your progress I also
really like how tonal offers personal
training in the form of motion sensing
technology thanks to the 17 sensors that
are located around the actual tonal so
this guidance is going to be based on
form range of motion and Pace while
you're working out so anytime you're
doing an exercise wrong or maybe you
just need to take a step back away from
the tonal it's going to tell you when to
do so I found this to be really helpful
as I was working out it was a couple
times out I was performing an exercise
wrong and I just didn't really even
notice that my form was a tad bit off
the only downside with this though is
that you know when you're doing an
exercise where your back is actually
facing tonal you have to listen for that
chime that goes off every single time
one of the prompts pops up on the screen
and then turn your head around just to
see what you did wrong
[Music]
so let's talk about some technology now
and if you haven't been paying attention
and you can't tell by now there's a lot
here with tonal so this is a 24 inch
touchscreen right here for you to scroll
through and select whatever class you
want to do the weight is done
electromagnetically within the tonal and
this is going to cap out at 200 pounds
but that's a one-to-one ratio so for
example if you have 200 pounds selected
well you better have 200 pounds of force
or else that way it is not going to move
you can also connect your Apple music or
your Spotify account directly to your
tonal that way you don't have to mess
with your phone at all while you're
working out the arms on the toenail are
going to move up and down allowing you
to work out your upper body and your
lower body but they also rotate in and
out which will come in handy during
specific exercises the cool thing is
though that your instructor is going to
tell you exactly where the arms need to
be positioned and the monitor itself has
indicate haters that show you where the
arms currently are positioned and where
they need to be I also really like how
the smart handles and the clamp that
goes on your barbell and your rope
attachment allow you to turn the digital
weight on and off whenever necessary and
don't forget the way it will
automatically increase to fit your
strength or decrease if you're
struggling that way you can really lift
until failure there's also a chains mode
that's going to make the weight kick in
at different moments whether you're
pushing it away from you or pulling it
to you just kind of depending on the
movement that you're doing this is also
going to allow you to give your best at
all times
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
with tonal you've got a mixture of
plastic and steel here I did in fact
chat with the tonal rep but they weren't
able to tell me the gauge steel that
they used on the framework right here
it's a little over four feet tall just
under two feet wide and it hangs out
about five inches or so from your wall
and since it you know once again it does
have to be mounted remember your studs
need to be around 16 inches apart or 24
inches apart anything bigger or smaller
than that which is simply not gonna work
now obviously the monitor right here is
made from glass so you could potentially
break it if something were to hit it so
definitely just want to be careful with
it that's a chunk of change that you
don't want to replace your smart handles
and your barbell are both made from
steel while the Rope attachment is
pretty much exactly what you'll find at
any gym you walk into and your foam
roller your yoga mat and your weight
bench are all about what you would
expect from any other ones out there as
well
all right guys let's go and do a quick
walk around with the tonal now and I'm
just going to show you basically how
everything functions so when you go to
the home screen you're going to find a
lot of different workouts right here on
the on the get go there's trending for
your goal trending this week as well as
new workouts that have gotten uploaded
they're going to be right here on this
home page now if you go to explore
there's a lot of different options for
you as well there's a for you page this
is a bunch of different programs that
are based around you know your goals
specifically and it's all broken apart
right here too as you can see chest
shoulders back triceps biceps I mean
everything is right here most popular by
strength high intensity yoga there's a
lot of different things here I also
really like though if you go to workouts
you know there's everything is
categorized from strength to boxing to
Family Fitness kickboxing there's a lot
of different stuff for you to choose
from right here and this is you know
more new workouts trending and popular
workouts as well right here
I really like how if you go to filters
all these different filters you can
select from so you can go from type of
Coach you want whoever that may be you
can go to duration body region muscle
group you know completed workouts to
save workouts all that's going to be
right here for you to select and that's
a really nice touch now if you go to
programs you know there's a bunch of
different ones for you to choose from as
well there's power building go big or go
home too there's a lot of different ones
right here and there's a coaches tab
that way you can just find all the
coaches that are on here and there's a
lot and you can scroll through it so
there's one specifically that you like
they lead the classes in a you know
specific way that you like they're right
here you can find all of their classes I
grew up on the top right right here is
the custom this is where you're going to
create your own custom workout programs
that's a really nice touch you know you
can do your own splits for the week
really whatever you want to do it's
going to be right here so you pull down
on this bar right here from the top this
is where you control your brightness
your volume your Bluetooth you can
connect your smart handles and that
clamp right here as well as make your
tunnel go to sleep and even adjust your
music settings all right let's go ahead
and break down all these accessories for
you as well I'm going to go ahead and
kick this off with the foam roller and
the yoga mat these are both pretty basic
and pretty much exactly what you'll find
all across the market now with this
barbell it's pretty cool the knurling
it's you do have a bit of a knurling
right here to provide you some sort of
grip but it's a little passive in my
opinion it's better than nothing though
now this is that clamp I was talking
about as you can see it just goes right
on your barbell it's super easy to put
it on and take it off just simply open
it up and it's going to clamp right down
on there for you so that button right
here that's the smart technology that's
what's going to kick in the weight or
turn it off whenever necessary and this
is also able to go onto your rope
attachment as well which is pretty nice
now speaking of the Rope attachment
this is also pretty standard it's a
nylon rope it's pretty much what you're
going to find in every single commercial
gym that you go in however I really do
like these smart handles right here now
these are really cool so you have that
button right here that's what's going to
be same thing as the clamp allow you to
turn the weight on or off with just a
simple click of a button but you know
before you do all that it has to be
paired up to your tonal so I'm going to
show you how to do that so you pull down
on this bar right here click on this
smart accessories button click add new
now as that's searching just click and
hold this button right here and it's
going to connect right away now if it
doesn't do it the first time just simply
repeat that process and it'll work all
right so to connect your attachments to
the cable arms it's pretty easy you're
just going to slide this right into that
opening right here give it a Twist and
no matter how hard you pull it's not
going to come out and to take it out
it's just reverse order twist it pull it
out and it's really easy to do now I'm
going to show you how to adjust the arms
so to make them go up and down there's a
lever right here you just simply pull on
it that's going to allow it to go down
or up
as you need it to do there's a button
right here on the side click that in and
you'll be able to rotate it out or in
that's going to be you know varying
across all the workouts you do and
there's this little guy right here you
pull out on it and that's what makes it
go up
or down for your workouts
[Music]
okay so who should purchase the tonal
well if you're new to Fitness and you
don't really know what you're doing I
think you're going to love that every
single class is led by an instructor and
they're going to show you the proper way
to perform every single exercise if
you're somebody like myself and you love
competition you kind of Thrive off of it
I think you're going to love the monthly
leaderboard it's going to pin you head
to head to the rest of the tunnel
community over a 30-day span and if
you're tight on space and still want to
have some sort of home gym I think this
is a really good option for you
especially because you know it doesn't
take up a whole lot of space especially
when the arms are folded in
okay so who should not purchase tonal
well let's talk about the money first
you know once again you'll be spending
four thousand dollars on just this one
piece of equipment and that's a lot of
money so if you don't want to do that
then you know I'd advise you don't do
that and look for some cheaper
alternatives this is also going to come
down to some personal preference as well
one of those people who loves working
out with a barbell or you know maybe
grabbing a classic pair of dumbbells if
you have the amount of space for all
that gear then I'd suggest going up
finding all of that gear and lastly it
really comes down to weight resistance
once again tonal Max is out at 200
pounds it's still in a one-to-one ratio
meaning you have to have that amount of
force to be able to move that amount of
weight but eventually you will run into
the problem of not having enough weight
resistance and that's something you
really won't have to worry about with a
barbell and even with some dumbbells
foreign
well that's a wrap on today's review
over the tonal home gym this thing's
honestly a beast and you're gonna feel
the burn while you're working out this
is a great space saving option for a lot
of people out there since it only
requires around seven square feet of
space or so to get a proper workout in
200 pounds of resistance may not seem
like a lot for everybody but since it
does in fact operate on a one-to-one
ratio it's going to be plenty for a lot
of y'all watching the companion app is a
great tool allows you to track your
progress over time the smart technology
is an awesome feature in my opinion and
it allows you to turn the weight on or
off with just a simple click of a button
and remember tonal is going to adapt to
your strength level and increase your
weight resistance over time that way you
can actually progressively overload your
muscles thanks for watching everybody I
hope this video was really helpful and
then I was able to show you exactly what
tonal brings to the table as always stay
tuned for my next video but for now head
over to barbin.com and you can read more
about this awesome product right here
all you have to do is search bar Bend
tonal home gym review you'll find
everything that I talked about here
today I'll see y'all next time
[Music]